University Railroad Collection 1997.0041
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
- Series I: Papers, undated, 1841-1993
  - Penn Central, Northeastern Region, TimeTable no. 4, for Employes Only, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Constitution and By-Laws of the American Train Dispatchers Association, 1971, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Penn Central Metropolitan Region Timetable No. 2, for employes only, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Penn Central, Northeastern Region, TimeTable no. 5, for Employes Only, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Penn Central Post, Special Issue: The Flood (1972 August-September) -- damage to the railroad from Tropical Storm Agnes in 1972 June (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Penn Central, Northeastern Region, TimeTable no. 6, for Employes Only, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Penn Central Metropolitan Region, Timetable No. 4, for employes only, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Amtrak East Coast Schedules (Passenger), 1973 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Penn Central, Northeastern Region, List of Reportable Locations (Stations-Yards-Sidings) for Use in Tabs Car Reporting System, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Consolidated Rail Corporations (Conrail), Northeastern Region, Timetable no. 7, for Employes Only, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Penn Central Metropolitan Region Timetable No. 6, for employes only, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Brotherhood of Railway, Airline and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express and Station Employes, Constitution of the Grand Lodge and Statutes for the Government of Lodges; Protective Laws and T.C. Division By-Laws, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Consolidated Rail Corporation (Conrail), Metropolitan Region, Timetable no. 7, for Employes Only, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Amtrak, Northeast Corridor Region, Fire Prevention and Protection Rules, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Amtrak, Complaint Procedures Handbook, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Amtrak, Northeast Corridor Region, Timetable no. 2, for employees only, 1977 October 30 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Amtrak, Northeast Corridor Region, Timetable no. 2 (special instructions), for employees only, 1977 November 20 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Consolidated Rail Corporation (Conrail), Northeastern region, Timetable no. 1, for employees only, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Amtrak, Northeast Corridor Region, Timetable no. 3, for employees only, 1978 October 29 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Amtrak Operating Rules and Instructions, with a Record of Examination for Paul LaBerge, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - The Administration of the Passenger Operation Services of the New Haven Railroad, 1966-1976, by Joseph A. Bongiorno, written as a graduate internship paper for St. John's University, 1980s (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Consolidated Rail Corporation (Conrail), Metropolitan region, Timetable no. 1, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Amtrak Northeast Corridor, Timetable no. 2, 1980 October 26 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Amtrak Tours: South East Escorted West Group tour brochure, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Consolidated Rail Corporation (Conrail), Rules of the Transportation Department, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - Amtrak Operating Rules and Instructions, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 74)
  - Amtrak, Northeast Corridor Region, Timetable no. 5, for employees only, 1983 October 30 (Box 5, Folder 75)
  - National Railroad Passenger Corporation ( Amtrak), Summary of the Changes in the Revised Amt-1, Amt-2, Amt-3, Amt-4, and Employee Timetable, Effective February 6, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - Amtrak, Northeast Corridor, Timetable no. 1, for employees only, 1984 February 6 (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - Amtrak Operating Rules and Instructions, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 78)
  - Amtrak Rules of Conduct, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 79)
  - Metro-North Commuter Railroad Rules of the Operating Department, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 80)
  - Amtrak, Northeast Corridor Region Timetable for employees only, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 81)
  - Amtrak, Northeast Corridor Region Timetable for employees only, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 82)
  - Metro-North Commuter Railroad, Timetable No. 2, for employees only, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 83)
  - Amtrak, Transportation Department report on Stamford, Connecticut, Center Island Platforms, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 84)
  - Draft Environmental Impact Statement/Report, Volume 1: Northeast Corridor Improvement Project Electrification - New Haven, Connecticut, to Boston, Massachusetts, published by the U.S. Department of Transportation Federal Railroad Administration, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 85)
  - Injury list, railroad safety bulletins, freight reports and waybills, 1872-1948 (Box 52, Folder 130)
    Materials include: Monthly freight reports and receipt of the New Haven & Northampton Railroad, 1872-1876; Waybills for freight from Westfield, Massachusetts, and Fishkill, New York, to Simsbury, Connecticut, 1904; Personal injury list for NHRR Hartford Division workmen, 1948; Safety bulletins, issued by J.A. Clancy, NHRR Supervisor of Safety, 1948
  - Central Vermont Railway baggage ticket, 1917 (Box 59, Folder 131)
  - Photocopies, track plans, station card, undated, 1991 (Box 59, Folder 133)
    Materials include: Photocopies of a 1991 article (title unknown, unknown publication) of the route of a walking trail on a former railroad bed, from Newtown, Connecticut; Hand drawn track plans, New Canaan Branch, undated; Card with list of times certain trains arrive at stations from Stamford, Connecticut, to Grand Central Terminal in New York, undated
  - Stock certificates, menus, manuals, maps, railroad freight car schedules, rule books, pamphlets, cloth patch, annual report, undated, 1920-2000 (Box 61)
    [Materials include: Three stock certificates, 1958 and undated; NHRR Travel Guide and Menu, November 1961 (stained); Menu for "Last Steam Train" on the NHRR, April 27, 1952; Issue of Railfan, December 1977 (story about NHRR FL9s); Carload Routing Manual for New York, Ontario and Western Railway, 1956; 2 maps of NHRR system (undated but likely before 1927); Blank cash fairs collection book; 1945 NHRR annual report; Freight train and package car schedules (1950-1967 scattered); Rules Governing the Employment of Track Foremen, April 1, 1920; Schedule and agreement with Firemen and Hostler, March 1, 1955; Station numbers pamphlet, October 15, 1944; Safety Rules, January 1, 1943; Cloth patch with NHNH&HRR logo, undated; Issue of Transportation with article about Meriden, Waterbury & Connecticut River Railroad, August 1953; 1910 Providence & Worcester Railroad annual report; Framed photo of The Comet (donor thinks his father is the person in the cab of the train), with article from 2000 about Comet]
- Series II: Track Diagrams and Charts, Maps, Equipment Blueprints, Surveyor's field books, Drawings, and Artwork, undated, 1841-1985
  - Subseries A: Track Diagrams, undated, 1841-1985
    - Notebook with hand drawn track diagram of portions of the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad system, undated (Box 7, Folder 86)
    - Track diagrams, Boston, Massachusetts, to Washington, D.C., undated (Box 7, Folder 87)
    - Pen Graft Distance Chart, Berea, New York, to Derby Junction, Connecticut, undated (Box 7, Folder 88)
    - Location of Plans for the Stockbridge & Pittsfield Railroad, undated (Box 32)
    - Berkshire Railroad, undated (Box 33)
    - West Stockbridge Railroad, undated (Box 34)
    - North & South Routes, Naugatuck to Hudson River, undated (Box 40)
    - New York & New England Railroad Location Plans, State Line to Mechanicsville, undated (Box 42)
    - Plans of Land purchased by the New Haven, New London and Stonington Railroad, in the Towns of Stonington and Groton, undated (Box 49)
    - Plans of Land purchased by the New Haven, New London and Stonington Railroad, in the Town of Groton, undated (Box 50)
    - Track diagrams, undated, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 89)
    - Manuscript track diagrams, Maybrook Line, Springfield Line, Shore Line, and Hartford Main Line of the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad, undated, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 90)
    - Berkshire Railroad ( Canaan, Connecticut, to West Stockbridge, Massachusetts), 1841 (Box 21)
    - Map and Profile -- Hartford, Providence & Fishkill Railroad, Willimantic to State-Line [Rhode Island], 1853 with revisions to 1873 (Box 16)
    - Danbury & Norwalk Railroad, Ridgefield Branch, 1869 (Box 39)
    - Holyoke & Westfield Railroad, 1871 (Box 20)
    - Map of the Windsor Locks & Suffield Railroad, 1875 (Box 41)
    - Plans of Land Purchased by the New York, Providence & Boston Railroad Company in the Towns of Warwick and Cranston, 1883-1884 (Box 48)
    - Plans of Land Purchased by the New York, Providence & Boston Railroad Company in the Towns of Exeter, North Kingston, part of Warwick and East Grenwich [sic], 1883-1884 (Box 51)
    - Location of Land of the Berkshire Railroad Company, county of Berkshire, Massachusetts, 1896 (Box 30)
    - Location of Lines, New Haven and Northampton Railroad Company, 1896 (Box 43)
    - Location of Lines, New Haven and Northampton Railroad Company, 1896 (Box 44)
    - Location of Lines, New Haven and Northampton Railroad Company, 1896 (Box 45)
    - Location of Lands of the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad, County of Hamden, Massachusetts, 1896 (Box 46)
    - Holyoke & Westfield Railroad to Hamden, Massachusetts, 1896 (Box 47)
    - Map of Lake Compounce Extension of the Meriden, Southington and Compounce Tramway in Hartford County, Connecticut, 1900 (Box 35)
    - Location of the Stockbridge & Pittsfield Railroad, 1905 (Box 31)
    - Grand Central Terminal Improvement, 1905-1906 (Box 22)
    - Assessor's Map, Sections 1-8, Blocks 1-3500, New Rochelle, New York, 1906 (Box 36)
    - Assessor's Map, Sections 1-2, Blocks 1-800, New Rochelle, New York, 1906 (Box 37)
    - Assessor's Map, Sections 3-4, Blocks 800-2000, New Rochelle, New York, 1906 (Box 38)
    - Map showing the line of the Harlem River and Portchester Railroad, Harlem River to New Rochelle Junction, Westchester County, New York, [1908] (Box 23)
    - Stamford/New Canaan - Wilton grade crossing elimination plan (blueprint), 1912 February (Box 52, Folder 121)
    - Abandonment of tracks in Deerfield, Massachusetts (valuation map 56.12/sheet 88), 1923 (Box 52, Folder 124)
    - Tracks and structures, Windsor Street Yard, Hartford, Connecticut, 1954 (Box 28, Folder 111)
    - Manuscript track diagrams, New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad, 1960s (Box 7, Folder 91)
    - Manuscript track diagrams, New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad and Penn Central, 1960s-1970s (Box 7, Folder 92)
    - Track diagrams, Willimantic, Connecticut, to Air Line Junction, including Colchester Branch ( New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad), 1960 April (Box 7, Folder 93)
    - Interlocking diagram, New Haven Region, Penn Central, 1969 July (Box 7, Folder 94)
    - Penn Central track diagrams, New Haven Railroad region, 1970s (Box 8, Folder 95)
    - Conrail system map, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 96)
    - Maintenance program and track chart, Metro-North Commuter Railroad, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 97)
    - Track diagrams, correspondence, legal opinion, undated, 1876, 1956 (Box 52, Folder 129)
      Track diagrams (undated, 1956) of New Haven Railroad right-of-way (incomplete but includes from areas throughout railroad system); one sheet of a 1876 legal opinion involving the Ridgefield & New York Railroad vs. James H. Brush, involving a subscription of shares of the company; letter (1876) from H.K. Scott, treasurer of the Ridgefield & New York Railroad to Sidney Reynolds of Greenwich, Connecticut, about payment on his stock, with envelope.
    - Blueprints and diagrams, 1922-1942, 1966 (Box 60, Folder 135)
      [Materials include: 1) "Characteristic Charts" of the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad, 1938-1942. Small blueprints. Shows "constituent lines, operating divisions, main line trackage, rail weights, etc." 2) "Condensed Profiles" of the NYNH&HRR, 1922. Small blueprints. 3) Hand drawn track diagrams of the NYNH&H RR system (photocopy). Some of the pages stamped "Copyright Fred F. Condon 1966"]
    - Hartford Division maps, undated (Volume 62)
    - Tracings of Hartford Division maps, undated (Volume 63)
    - Present Layout Cedar Hill Terminal (with classification yards photograph), undated, 1930 (Item 12)
  - Subseries B: Maps (unless otherwise noted all are associated with properties owned by the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad), undated, 1866-1970s
    - Blueprint map of the Norwalk, Connecticut, railroad station, undated (Box 52, Folder 118)
    - New York Harbor Terminals, undated (Item 11)
    - Map of Willimantic showing route of Central Vermont Railway, undated
    - Index Map of the Shore Line Electric Railway, Old Saybrook to Chester, Connecticut, undated
    - Copy of a geological survey map with the Shore Line Electric Railway route drawn on, with photographs of scenes from Old Saybrook to Chester, Connecticut, undated
    - Alterations and Additions to Old Passenger Station for Freight Facilities, Middletown, Connecticut, 1907 December
    - System Map of the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad, 1940s, with lines colored in of those parts of the system taken over by other successors of the railroad, 1970s
    - Part of the Nashawaug Water - Power Estate Situated in Killingly, Connecticut, and Brooklyn, Connecticut, belonging to Elisha Dyer, compiled from Various Surveys by Cushing and DeWitt, 1866 (Item 13)
    - Plan of Chester Hill, Mount Vernon, New York, 1869
    - Housatonic Railroad Company, Lenox Furnace, Massachusetts, from Surveys and Locations as Made by W.E. Pettee in 1885 With Village Locations in 1866 for Furnace Company
    - Hartford, Connecticut (small section including Asylum Street) (plan #16479, MF024080), 1898 August 29
    - Proposed Change of Tracks near Engine House at Hartford, Connecticut, (plan #16479, MF024080), 1899 April
    - Property of First Congregationalist Society and Town of Manchester, Connecticut, 1899 September
    - Proposed Change of Tracks, New Haven, Connecticut, (plan #11534, MF024590), 1901 May
    - Proposed Extension of Platform, etc., New Haven, Connecticut, New Haven Terminal, plan #11534, MF024591), 1902 August
    - Village of Rye [New York] Tax Map, 1915 July 22
    - Old Saybrook, Connecticut, Property Lines at Bridge Street, 1924 October
    - Proposed Central Boiler House, Lamberton Street Yard, New Haven, Connecticut, and Wash Borings (plan #15014, MF024075), 1927
    - Location of Line in the County of Barnstable by the Trustees of the Property of Old Colony Railroad in the Town of Bourne Under-the-General-Laws-of-Massachusetts (9 sheets), 1946 January 9
    - Plan Showing Property at Springfield, Massachusetts, (plan #6617, MF020653), 1948 January 2
    - Renewal of Air Lines, Cedar Hill Yard, New Haven, Connecticut, (plan #6632, MF019786), 1948 October 11
    - Renewal of Air Lines, Cedar Hill Yard, New Haven, Connecticut, (plan #6632, MF019787), 1948 October 11
    - Sanitary Hydrant Layout, No. 1 Yard, Dover Street, Boston, Massachusetts, 1949 June 1
    - Map of Sixpenny Island, [located on the Mystic River near Groton, Connecticut], 1971 September 16
    - [City of Providence, Rhode Island, and Town of East Providence, Rhode Island] (plan 16833, MF024107), undated (Item 14)
    - Property Lines at Bassett Avenue, Westchester, New York, undated
    - Additions to the Original Right of Way (plan 16520, MF024085), unidentified property but likely Belle Dock, New Haven, Connecticut, undated
    - Belle Dock, New Haven, Connecticut, (plan 16650, MF024089), undated
    - [Belle Dock, New Haven, Connecticut], (plan 16650, MF024092), undated
    - Belle Dock, New Haven, Connecticut, (plan 16650, MF024093), undated
    - Belle Dock, New Haven, Connecticut, (plan 16650, MF024094), 1897 July
    - Plan for Rebuilding Long Wharf, New Haven, Connecticut (plan 16064)
      - MF02460, 1899 August 14
      - MF02461, 1899 August 18
      - MF02462, 1899 August 17
    - Plan Showing Proposed Change of Tracks at Belle Dock, New Haven, Connecticut, (plan #16520, MF024090), 1899 February
    - Plan Showing Proposed Channell [sic], Belle Dock, New Haven, Connecticut, Belle Dock Bridge (plan #16520, MF024089), 1899 September
    - Plan Showing Tracks as Changed at Belle Dock, [ New Haven, Connecticut] (plan #16520, MF024088), 1899 October
    - 2nd Map of Franklin Park, Harrison, New York, 1903 July
    - Plan #3 Showing Proposed Freight Facilities and Additional Changes, Stonington, Connecticut, (plan #17325, MF024628), 1904 October
    - Plan #4 Showing Proposed Freight Facilities and Additional Changes, Stonington, Connecticut, (plan #17325, MF024629), 1904 November
    - Plan Showing Land at Russell's Crossing, New Haven, Connecticut, 1917 March
    - Land in Stonington, Connecticut, Plan Showing Water Front Property, 1918 September 6
    - Plan Showing Land at Russell's Crossing, New Haven, Connecticut, 1920 July
    - Property Lines at South Lyme, Connecticut, 1924 January
    - Map and Profile, Hartford, Providence & Fishkill Railroad, Willimantic to State-Line [Rhode Island], 1853 with revisions to 1873 (Box 16)
    - Location Plans, Stockbridge & Pittsfield Railroad, Vandeusenville to Pittsfield, 1880 (Box 25)
    - Property maps of the Dutchess County Railroad, Philadelphia & Reading Railroad Real Estate Department, 1893 (Box 24)
    - Maps of the Railroads of Connecticut to Accompany the Report of the Railroad Commissioners, 1891, 1893 (Item 12)
    - Blueprint for proposed masonry for bridge no. 7.71 on the Bronx & Pelham Parkway, 1906 (Box 52, Folder 120)
    - Plan showing Charles Street engine facilities, Providence, Rhode Island, 1917 (Box 52, Folder 122)
    - Track map for Montowese, Connecticut, 1959 (Box 52, Folder 127)
  - Subseries C: Equipment Blueprints, 1916-1943 (Box 9)
    - New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad equipment drawings
    - plan of slow board temporary slow boards bridge warning slow tracks (S-204)
    - tell-tale for bridge warning mitre rail joints at ends of bascule bridges (S-210)
    - trolley troughs (S-214)
    - safety line for station platform (S-302)
    - cast iron chimneys (S-306)
    - mail crane (S-326)
    - gates (S-402)
    - steel inter-track fence (S-403)
    - crossing gate lamp and hanger (S-405)
    - crossing gate lantern (S-405)
    - safety guard fence for use with tie tamper compressor (S-408)
    - conventional signs (S-602)
    - dimensions of turnouts (S-714)
    - tie plates switch bolts (S-825)
    - pole numbering (S-902)
    - rail rest (S-904)
    - roadbed cross-sections, stone and gravel ballast (S-906)
    - tie spacing and spiking (S-912)
    - tie boring (S-913)
    - hoops and lugs for wooden water tanks (S-1001)
    - smoke stack fire protection concrete sign posts whistle, ring and section letters and figures for signs and notices (S-1202)
    - figures for numbering switch stand targets (S-1203)
    - highway bridge loading signhighway crossing sign (S-1204)
    - numbering of bridges (S-1207)
    - danger and trespass signs (S-1208)
    - danger and warning signs (S-1209)
    - passing siding sign (S-1210)
    - yard limit sign (S-1211)
    - no dumping signs (S-1212)
    - stop sign - wood (S-1213)
    - parking lease sign (S-1214)
    - impure water sign (S-1217)
    - station driveway sign (S-1218)
    - highway crossing circuit signs station sign (S-1220)
    - spring switch sign (S-1221)
    - no parking sign (S-1223)
    - snowboard signs (S-1225)
    - distant warning sign (S-1226)
    - track wrenches (S-1301)
    - raising bar (S-1302)
    - tamping bar (S-1303)
    - claw bar (S-1305)
    - chisel point crow bar (S-1308)
    - tamping pick (S-1307)
    - clay pick (S-1308)
    - spike maul (S-1309)
    - railroad adze (S-1310)
    - shovel (S-1311)
    - turntable center bushing (at East Hartford, Connecticut)
    - diesel wrecking derrick
  - Subseries D: 32 Surveyor's field books, 1919-1927 (Box 29)
  - Subseries E: Drawings and Artwork, undated
    - Prints by William Dulmaine, Jr., undated (Box 10)
    - "The East Wind" -- Like a summer breeze "The East Wind" glides through a Putnam meadow. New Haven I-4 1396 leads the way toward the B&M [ Boston and Maine Railroad] and Maine's vacationland", (3 copies)
    - "Maybrook Bound" -- Alco FA-1 (NH Class DER2-A) leads a trio of units upgrade east of Poughquag Station, New York, with westbound Symbol Freight No. 7, as Advance B-2 descends on the eastbound iron (2 copies)
    - "Yellow Dog Extra" -- New Haven R2a 3507 highballs a Maine Potato Extra through drifting snow on the N&W [ Norfolk and Western Railroad] at N. Oxford, MA (2 copies)
    - "Flight of the Speed Witch" -- With New Haven Light Mountain R-1a #3339 on the point the westbound "Speed Witch" races through the night to "Hell Gate" and beyond (2 copies)
    - Other artwork, undated
    - Three drawings of New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad locomotives 0754, 1357, and 1611 by an artist identified as "Heidorn,", 1990s (Box 10)
    - "Hartford's First Station" -- line drawing, artist unidentified, undated (Box 15:, Folder 99)
- Series III: Photographs, 1890s, 1930s-1995
  - Glass negative of a New York and New England Railroad arch over North Main Street in Naugatuck, Connecticut, 1890s (Box 53)
  - Ten photographs taken by Joseph P. Boreskie of locomotives of the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad, 1930s (Box 26, Folder 104)
  - Railroad station surveys, mostly of railroad stations of the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad in Connecticut, with photographs by Charles Gunn, 1954-1955
    - New Haven District, Book C-1 -- Main Line: Stonington to Rowayton, Connecticut, 1954 (Box 54)
    - New Haven District, Book C-2 -- Main Line and Branch Lines (not including Pittsfield Branch): North Haven to Meriden, Middletown, Norwich to Danielson, Derby Shelton to Waterbury, Thomaston to Winsted, 1954 (Box 55)
    - New Haven District, Book C-3 -- Branch Line: Wall Street in Norwalk, Connecticut, to Pittsfield, Massachusetts, 1954 (Box 56)
    - New York District - Book E -- Main Line: Darien, Connecticut, to Mount Vernon, New York; Branch Line: Glenbrook - New Canaan, 1954-1955 (Box 57)
  - Four photographs of the railroad station in New Haven, Connecticut, circa 1960s or 1970s (Box 26, Folder 105)
  - Photograph of the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad Police Department, taken after the takeover by Penn Central, 1969 January 24 (Box 26, Folder 98)
  - Photographs of New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad cars taken in Gettysburg, Pennsylvania, and Pueblo, Colorado, 1982, 1995 (Box 26, Folder 108)
  - Trolleys and locomotives
  - Photograph of Tommy Lyons, train engineer, being congratulated on his retirement by NHRR President George Alpert, 1956 December (Box 52, Folder 130)
  - Two photographs (undated, ca. 1960s) of scenes on the New Haven Railroad -- commuters standing along tracks with locomotive in foreground (snow scene) and men standing atop passenger cars, presumably repairing electrical wiring (Box 59, Folder 133)
- Series IV: Gift of Gary Carlquist, undated, 1897-1984 (Box 27)
  - Materials include a train crew form book (all forms are blank), circa 1907; track plans, possibly for the Boston & Albany Railroad, undated; letters and photographs recognizing the long service of New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad employee Matthew Corrigan, 1950s; Operating rule books for employees of the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad, New York Central Railroad, PennCentral, Conrail, and Metro-North Commuter Railroad, 1950s-1984; an annual report of the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad, 1897; Hand drawn track plans of New York, New Haven Hartford Railroad route from North Haven, Connecticut, to Springfield, Massachusetts, undated; keys and metal ticket punchers, undated; and three drawings of New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad trains done by The Hobby Center, Inc. (1975)